#### RAJAN GYAWALI

Kathmandu, Nepal Email: <a href="mailto:rajangyawali.np@gmail.com">rajangyawali.np@gmail.com</a>
Phone: +977-9851198070 Webpage: <a href="http://rajangyawali.github.io/">http://rajangyawali.github.io/</a>

An independent and self-motivated, a research enthusiast with proven skills in Computer Vision and Machine Learning. Graduated with a Master's degree in "**Information and Communication Engineering**" from the Institute of Engineering, Pulchowk Campus, Tribhuvan University, Kathmandu, Nepal.

## **EDUCATION**

### Pulchowk Campus, Tribhuvan University

Lalitpur, Nepal

MSc. Information and Communication Engineering, 90.13%

2019

- Completed two year's programme as a research student
- Major Subjects: Color Image Technology, Image Processing, Machine Learning & Pattern Recognition
- Project Work on "Convolutional Neural Networks for Multiclass Face Recognition"
- Thesis research on "Employee Face Recognition by Region Proposal Networks and Faster R-CNN"

#### Himalaya College of Engineering, Tribhuvan University

Lalitpur, Nepal

B.E. Electronics and Communication Engineering, 82.06%

2016

- Major Subjects: Discrete Mathematics, Artificial Intelligence, Data Mining, Big Data Technologies, Analog and Digital Signal Processing
- Minor Project on "Smart Irrigation System"
- Final Year Project on "Brain Controlled Wheelchair"

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Tenured Government Telecommunication Engineer** | Nepal Telecom (May 2018 – present)

- Scripting to automate the daily redundant tasks of report management and network status
- Analysis of key performance indicators of network elements with a fully automated analytics system, "Wireless KPI Analytics Tool", developed and maintained by me
- Installation, configuration and commissioning of 2G, 3G BTS Nodes and LTE eNodeBs
- Preparing estimate, installation, performance report, and documentation of ongoing projects
- Providing training on "Python Programming", "Data Analytics and Visualizations" to other employees of the company

### **Lecturer** | Himalaya College of Engineering (Oct 2016 – May 2018)

- Involved in teaching undergraduate courses up to class size of 48 students. Subjects included: "Electromagnetics", "Computer Graphics", "Signal Processing", "Digital Communications" and "Wireless Communications"
- Prepared course materials including laboratory experiments, lectures, exams, homework, and practice problems
- Led weekly laboratory and/or problem-solving and discussion sections for groups of 16-24 students
- Supervised students in final year projects, graded exams and weekly assignments
- Provided training on "*Python Programming*" to undergraduate students of Computer Engineering and Electronics & Communication Engineering

### **Part Time Lecturer** | Engineering Colleges and Private Institutions (May 2018 – present)

- Involved in teaching various courses to undergraduate students of Engineering, from different engineering colleges of Tribhuvan University at different points of time
- Involved in teaching students, preparing for "Public Service Commission"

### **Python Programmer** | (Dec 2015 – present)

- Involved in teaching Python language to students, colleagues with focus on data analysis and visualizations
- Involved in building REST APIs and websites using Python, Django

### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### **Pulchowk Campus, Tribhuvan University**

Lalitpur, Nepal

Master's Researcher

2018 - 2019

- Studied about different image processing methodologies and machine learning algorithms
- Used Convolutional Neural Networks for multi-class face recognition as a project work
- Developed a Deep Learning model for employee face recognition with standard dataset, used *Region Proposal Networks* for image segmentation and *Faster R-CNN* for classification and tested the model with my own primary dataset, as a master's thesis

## **PUBLICATION**

• R. Gyawali, D. R. Pant, "An Approach for the Employee Face Recognition by RPN and Faster R-CNN Techniques", IOE Graduate Conference, Volume 6, May 2019.

## <u>SKILLS</u>

Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Git, Plotly, Dash, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Javascript

### **LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE**

- Founded a forum under the name "*Himalaya Coders Forum*" with the aim to provide programming training to 1<sup>st</sup> year and 2<sup>nd</sup> year students of the college during my 4<sup>th</sup> year study at Himalaya College of Engineering
- Actively participated in various activities of "Robotics Club" at college during my undergraduate studies

#### TRAINING and ONLINE COURSES

- Participated in 2 months training course on "Data Science with Python", Leapfrog Academy, Kathmandu, March May 2016
- Participated in 20 days training on "*EUTRAN eNodeB Training*" at Huawei Global Training Center, China, June 8 July 7, 2019
- Participated in 2 days workshop on "*Internet of Things*" at Deerwalk Inc., Kathmandu, February 29 March 1, 2020
- Took course on "Python for Everybody" and "Django for Everybody", offered by Coursera, 2020
- Took Course on "Data Science" and "Applied Data Science" offered by IBM on Coursera, 2020

# **ACHIEVEMENTS AND AWARDS**

- "Best Project Award", for my undergraduate final year project "Brain Controlled Wheelchair", in the "nec project exhibition" organized by Nepal Engineering College, 2016
- "Mahatma Gandhi Scholarship", awarded by Indian Embassy, Nepal, 2009-2011
- "Golden Jubilee Scholarship", awarded by Indian Embassy, Nepal, 2011-2013
- Full Scholarship at Himalaya College of Engineering, for pursuing undergraduate degree
- Regular Scholarship at Pulchowk Campus, for pursuing graduate degree
- Ranked 3<sup>rd</sup> in undergraduate results of "Electronics and Communication Engineering" offered by Institute of Engineering, Tribhuvan University
- Ranked 1<sup>st</sup> in graduate results of "Information and Communication Engineering", Pulchowk Campus

## **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that the information given above is correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Rajan Gyawali